"The Stranger I Met" Episode 15
'내가 만난 낯선 사람' 15회
(Wu Jindong)
(우진동)
(Kyung Gi Joo)
(주경기)
(a stranger I met)
(내가 만난 낯선 사람)
(Bangbang Teahouse)
(방방찻집)
(Episode 15, the reason why I can’t leave)
(15화 내가 떠날 수 없는 이유)
Haijun
하이준
Father
아버지
Is this because Hae Joon will come back anyway?
어차피 해준이 돌아올 것이기 때문인가?
He was very good to me when he was here
그 사람이 여기에 있을 때 나에게 아주 잘 대해줬어요
Just wait like crazy
미친 듯이 기다려
The son asked him if he would come back
아들이 다시 오겠냐고 물었어요
really annoying
정말 짜증나
what exactly is it?
정확히 무엇입니까?
what is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
Why did you come to me?
나한테 왜 왔어?
they are talking about looking for me
그들은 나를 찾는 것에 대해 이야기하고 있습니다
(Part 15)
(15부)
(Congratulations to the 1988 Seoul Olympics )
(1988년 서울올림픽을 축하합니다 .)
This news is about teachers
이번 소식은 선생님에 관한 소식이에요
I saw the defendant's face
피고인의 얼굴을 보았습니다.
you do not say
당신은 말하지 않는다
I'll come to your house at noon
정오에 너희 집에 갈게
Anyway, my plan was ruined.
어쨌든 내 계획은 망가졌어.
I really want to hear
정말 듣고 싶어요
I'm here to tell you this
나는 이것을 당신에게 말하려고 여기에 있습니다
But there is still one person without you
그래도 너 없는 한 사람이 있어
And the defendant
그리고 피고인은
What
무엇
Although I often miss the things nearby
근처에 있는 것들이 자주 그리워지긴 하지만
I was told to stay in my house and come to me to inquire.
나는 내 집에 머물 면서 나에게 와서 문의하라는 말을 들었습니다 .
What do you want me to do?
내가 무엇을 하기를 바라나요?
What are you talking about now?
지금 무슨 말을하는거야?
you really don't know
당신은 정말로 모른다
Brother Yun Wule
윤울 형제
The principal's son said
교장 아들이 말했다.
He is the culprit
그 사람이 범인이에요
Why did you come?
왜 왔나요?
far away
멀리
Lacquer water
옻나무
i know where to go
난 어디로 가야할지 알아
Lee Joo Young Lee Kyun Il
이주영 이균일
The murder of the Youbum brothers
유범 형제 살해 사건
Conspiracy to murder Lee Sun-il and Yoon Hye-joon
이선일·윤혜준 살해음모
Yun Yunwu was arrested
윤윤우가 체포됐다
From now on I'm going to search the house for evidence.
이제부터 증거를 찾기 위해 집을 수색하겠습니다.
Come
오다
Is the director okay?
감독님 괜찮으세요?
No. How did this happen?
아뇨. 어떻게 이런 일이 일어났나요?
Dong-seok asks what’s going on
무슨 일인지 묻는 동석
Although teacher Yin Hyejun was sent to the hospital
인혜준 선생님은 병원으로 이송됐지만
I haven't regained consciousness yet
아직 의식을 회복하지 못했어요
Haijun
하이준
Wait, how did this happen?
잠깐만요, 이게 어떻게 된 거죠?
Miss
놓치다
Haijun
하이준
What happens to the defendant now?
이제 피고인은 어떻게 되나요?
check carefully
주의 깊게 확인하세요
I have to make sure I pay off my debt
빚을 확실히 갚아야 해요
That is..
그건..
I hope I can be Mr. Yoon Hye Jun
나도 윤혜준씨가 됐으면 좋겠다
If I get caught, I guess it's all over
잡히면 다 끝날 것 같아
without any sin
아무 죄도 없이
Those who died miserably
비참하게 죽은 이들
I don't know if I can pay for all these sins..but still
이 모든 죄값을 다 치를 수 있을지는 모르겠지만.. 그래도
for him now
지금 그 사람을 위해서
I have to say it because I feel like this is something that will never end with me for the rest of my life
평생 끝나지 않을 일인 것 같아서 말해야 해요.
I'm afraid of that
그게 두렵다
How could I give him such an answer?
내가 어떻게 그 사람에게 그런 대답을 할 수 있겠는가?
I'm very sorry about this
이 점에 대해 매우 죄송합니다.
so
그래서
Did he really mean that Hye-jun was caused by him?
정말 혜준이 자기 때문에 생겼다는 뜻 인가요 ?
When Yunwu comes back
윤우가 돌아오면
I went to the airport by myself
나 혼자 공항에 갔어
After four hours of driving , I...
4시간의 운전 끝에 나는...
He drove next to him
그 사람이 옆에 차를 몰았어
Everyone in the village was dead by then
그때쯤 마을 사람들은 모두 죽어 있었다
when we return to the bubbling place
우리가 버블링 장소로 돌아갈 때
I met him, but how?
그 사람을 만났는데 어떻게요?
Didn't the director check the passport?
원장님이 여권을 확인하지 않으셨나요?
A passport?
여권?
Yunwu returns to this village for the first time
윤우는 처음으로 이 마을에 돌아왔다.
Earlier than the director knew
감독이 아는 것보다 일찍
He was never suspected from the beginning
그는 처음부터 의심을 받은 적이 없었다
that's why
그렇기 때문에
Yunwu deceived everyone from the beginning
윤우는 처음부터 모두를 속였다
Until the day I return to this village
내가 이 마을로 돌아가는 그날까지
When, where and what kind of crime was committed?
언제, 어디서, 어떤 종류 의 범죄가 저질러졌습니까?
You must say it now with your mouth
이제 입으로 말해야지
sick
아픈
not getting smarter
더 똑똑해지지 않아
Must say it
꼭 말해야 해
He said he was sick
자기가 아프다고 하더군요
The hand that uncle threw
삼촌이 던진 손
sorry
죄송합니다
I think I need therapy
치료가 필요할 것 같아요
Can't you call me daddy?
아빠라고 불러주면 안 돼?
Don't you know where this is now?
지금 여기가 어디인지 모르시나요?
Don't you know why you are here?
당신이 여기 왜 왔는지 모르시나요?
I am not sure
잘 모르겠습니다
Uncle, can you explain?
삼촌, 설명해 주실 수 있나요?
- What - like a witness.
- 뭐 - 증인 같은 거요.
If you show me something like
나에게 다음과 같은 것을 보여주면
Why?
왜?
Is there no evidence?
증거가 없나요?
Now, my house and my room
이제 내 집 과 내 방
Search is enough
검색하면 충분하다
But don’t you see anything?
그런데 아무것도 안 보이나요?
of course not
당연히 아니지
because i didn't do it
내가 하지 않았으니까
correct?
옳은?
How are you?
어떻게 지내세요?
do you remember?
기억 나니?
What happened to the defendant?
피고인에게 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
It's all over now
이제 다 끝났어
Detective Shi Badong took it and inspected it
Shi Badong 형사가 그것을 가져와 조사했습니다.
Will you continue to look away from me?
계속 나를 외면할 건가요?
sorry
죄송합니다
You hurt your family like this
이렇게 가족에게 상처를 주다니
this is my father
우리 아빠 야
I came from that disgusting one too.
나도 그 역겨운 곳에서 왔어.
That despicable person hurt you too
그 비열한 사람이 너에게도 상처를 줬어
Why are you apologizing for this?
이걸 왜 사과하는 거야?
you and me
너와 나
Everything our family has been through
우리 가족이 겪었던 모든 일들
not a single error
단 한 번의 오류도 아닌
So don't say such things again
그러니까 다시는 그런 말 하지 마
Don't think so
그렇게 생각하지 마세요
He didn't know where he came from
그 사람은 자신이 어디서 왔는지 몰랐어요
Nothing has changed for me
나한테는 아무것도 변한 게 없어
Thanks for reminding me
상기시켜주셔서 감사합니다
director
감독
The culprit is 100% certain
범인은 100% 확실해요
After entering the trap, we were imprisoned in
함정에 들어간 후 우리는 감옥에 갇혔습니다.
As soon as he knew I was there, he ran away
그 사람은 내가 거기 있다는 걸 알자마자 도망갔어
And you're trying to escape in your car
그리고 당신은 차를 타고 탈출을 시도하고 있어요
I'm injured
부상당했어요
If the entry date is incorrect
입력 날짜가 잘못된 경우
There are a few points worth doubting
의심해볼 만한 몇 가지 점이 있다
but
하지만
no concrete evidence
구체적인 증거는 없다
He is light because he knows it
그는 그걸 알기 때문에 가볍다
It appears to have been carefully cleaned to prevent the police from discovering it.
경찰이 발견하지 못하도록 꼼꼼하게 청소를 한 것으로 보인다.
I asked if there was any evidence
증거가 있냐고 물었더니
How about handwriting?
손글씨는 어때요?
Have you checked that the handwriting matches the handwriting in the message?
손글씨가 메시지의 손글씨와 일치하는지 확인하셨나요?
what are these?
이것들은 무엇입니까?
at the same time
동시에
Wu Yun sent it to me from the United States
Wu Yun이 미국에서 나에게 보냈습니다.
weekly letters
주간 편지
this is what i have
이게 내가 가진 거야
(Zhou Airlines)
(저우항공)
(Arrived in the U.S. and made arrangements)
(미국에 도착해서 준비를 했습니다)
This is it
이거 야
The handwriting is different from the Yun Wu I know
내가 아는 윤우랑 글씨체가 다르네
Because I am the only one who knows this handwriting
이 글씨체를 아는 사람은 나뿐이니까
in this whole world
이 세상 전체에서
I'm the only one who knows
아는 사람은 나뿐이야
Because of this handwriting
이 손글씨 때문에
Watch now
지금보기
others will find out
다른 사람들도 알게 될 거야
Message left by the defendant to the victim
피고인이 피해자에게 남긴 메시지
The handwriting is there
손글씨가 거기에 있어요
Because it's the same
똑같으니까
handwriting
필적
It's not easy to lie when you want to
거짓말하고 싶을 때 거짓말을 하는 것은 쉽지 않다
That's why I'm confused
그래서 난 혼란스러워
Just like when Gomin was fat
고민이 뚱뚱했을 때처럼
Generally speaking, if there is handwritten material
일반적으로 손으로 쓴 자료가 있는 경우
This can be compared with each other
이는 서로 비교할 수 있다.
No matter how I search, there is no result
아무리 찾아봐도 결과가 안나오네요
After the news airs, find your woman
뉴스가 나온 후 네 여자를 찾아봐
The owner of an ordinary teahouse
평범한 찻집 주인
Did he tell you that Yunwu was the culprit?
윤우가 범인 이라고 말했나요 ?
know something from him
그에게서 뭔가를 알아
Although I try hard to find
열심히 찾아보지만
I wonder where they disappeared after the teahouse closed.
찻집이 문을 닫은 후 어디로 사라졌는지 궁금합니다.
Absolutely untraceable
절대 추적 불가능
That's it, it's enough to leave the village
그게 다야, 마을을 떠나면 충분하다
Because he wants to leave
그 사람이 떠나고 싶어하니까
What's that word?
그 단어는 무엇입니까?
want to be different from others
남들과 다르고 싶어
I will write something special
특별한 글을 쓰겠습니다
It's time to write me a letter
나에게 편지를 쓸 시간이다
He said he could write with his other hand
다른 손으로도 글을 쓸 수 있다고 하더군요
I thought it was just a fantasy
난 그냥 환상인줄 알았는데
Because he thinks so
그 사람이 그렇게 생각하니까
i like it better
난 그게 더 좋아
But one day
그런데 어느 날
Detectives come looking for him
형사들이 그를 찾으러 온다
(The clouds dance to Li Chao'a)
(구름이 Li Chao'a에 맞춰 춤을 춥니다)
A message from Matchbox appears
매치박스에서 보낸 메시지가 나타납니다.
Because our theater doesn't match
우리 극장이 안 맞아서
If it's just a customer
그냥 고객이라면
I don't know if I still remember
아직도 기억하는지 모르겠어
I remembered it immediately
바로 생각났어요
Because I am the only one who knows this handwriting
이 글씨체를 아는 사람은 나뿐이니까
in this case..
이 경우에는..
Why didn't you tell me then?
그때 왜 나한테 말하지 않았어?
Unless you're not...
당신이 아닌 이상...
I want to escape
탈출하고 싶어
this time
이 시간
I always wanted to escape
난 항상 탈출하고 싶었어
Although he did want to escape
비록 그는 탈출하고 싶었지만
Yoon Hye-joon
윤혜준
As soon as I told him
내가 그에게 말하자마자
but not enough evidence
하지만 증거가 충분하지 않다
Wu Yun is a smart man
우윤은 똑똑한 사람이다
Making mistakes is not enough
실수하는 것만으로는 충분하지 않습니다.
Besides
게다가
(Zhou Airlines)
(저우항공)
- That's why.. - You
- 그래서.. - 당신
What's the real reason you came to see me ?
나를 만나러 온 진짜 이유는 무엇입니까 ?
detective
형사
what
무엇
Owner of Bom Bom Tea House
봄봄찻집 주인
Haven't there been enough cases where I helped you find him ?
내가 당신을 도와준 사례는 많지 않나요 ?
Well
잘
Because he looks important
그 사람이 중요해 보이니까
Although we are the same now
지금 우리는 똑같지만
especially for him
특히 그 사람에게는
Unless it's not...
그렇지 않은 이상...
if you leave the village
마을을 떠나면
I don't even know if I'm going to the grocery store
식료품점에 갈지조차 모르겠어요
by my grandfather
나의 할아버지에 의해
I'll go see if I can investigate.
조사할 수 있는지 보러 가겠습니다.
Thank you Yin Yan
이옌님 감사합니다
If you are the owner of Bom Bom Teahouse, you must have seen
봄봄찻집 오너라면 한 번쯤은 보셨을 텐데요 .
Sitting alone in front of the grocery store for a long time
마트 앞에 혼자 오랫동안 앉아 있다
The girl just sat alone, feeling sad
그 소녀는 슬픈 기분으로 혼자 앉아 있었어요
I sat with you for a while
나는 당신과 잠시 앉아 있었어요
I didn't see it until I got on the bus
버스에 탑승할 때까지 보지 못했어요
So I look at where I'm going and which bus I'm going to take
그래서 어디로 갈지, 어떤 버스를 탈지 살펴봅니다.
I have no idea
나는 전혀 모른다
I can't remember clearly
기억이 잘 안 나네요.
Thanks
감사해요
How are you?
어떻게 지내세요?
What
무엇
Because of the director's son?
감독 아들 때문에?
To be honest, I still can't believe it
솔직히 아직도 믿기지 않아요
director
감독
a truly good man
정말 좋은 사람
Such a good life gave birth to a son
이렇게 좋은 삶이 아들을 낳았어요
How to do it?
어떻게 하나요?
from the other side
반대편에서
I also pray that guy is really the culprit
그 사람이 진짜 범인이길 기도해요
Why?
왜?
If so, the suspect has been captured
그렇다면 용의자는 체포됐다.
it's all over
모든 끝났어
other people..
다른 사람..
I don't feel like my child anymore
더 이상 내 아이가 아닌 것 같아요
to anyone in the world
세상 누구에게나
no family
가족 없음
like this
이와 같이
I don't want to feel it
나는 그것을 느끼고 싶지 않다
Mr. Yin
인 씨
Thank you very much again
다시 한번 진심으로 감사드립니다
thank you for catching me
날 잡아줘서 고마워
thank you so much for ending it
마무리해주셔서 정말 감사합니다
Yes
예
No evidence?
증거 없음?
Why?
왜?
I remember my father's handwriting
나는 아버지의 손글씨를 기억한다
No
아니요
I've never seen my father's handwriting
나는 아버지의 손글씨를 본 적이 없다.
grandfather
할아버지
What's this?
이건 뭐죠?
He said he can study now
이제 공부해도 된다고 하더군요
My father sent me oil, grandpa
아버지가 기름을 보내주셨어요, 할아버지
(From Yoon Yoon Woo to Yoon Hae Joon)
(윤윤우에서 윤해준으로)
(Dear son Hae Joon comes)
(사랑하는 아들 해준이 온다)
Such a disgusting guy
정말 역겨운 놈이네
just know
그냥 알아
I knew everything then
그때는 다 알았어
Heejun
희준
(Zhou Airlines)
(저우항공)
(I hope you will definitely use the diary I gave you as a gift)
(제가 선물해드린 다이어리 꼭 활용하시길 바랍니다)
how did you do it?
넌 어떻게 그걸 했니?
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
Haejun, that's...
해준아 그게...
Defendant's handwritten witness
피고인의 자필 증인
Why not burn it all?
왜 다 태워버리지 않겠습니까?
I know
알아요
I know this is crazy
나도 이게 미친 짓이라는 걸 알아
I know it's a big sin, but
큰 죄인 건 알지만
But what?
근데 뭐?
The rest of your life depends on it
당신의 남은 인생은 그것에 달려 있습니다
Because it depends on your future
왜냐하면 그것은 당신의 미래에 달려 있기 때문입니다.
i can't do anything
난 아무것도 할 수 없어
To me this is your best choice
나에게는 이것이 최선의 선택 이다
Now that the baby is in the mother's belly, you...
이제 아기가 엄마 뱃속에 있으니...
Born the son of a murderer who killed three people
세 사람을 죽인 살인자의 아들로 태어나다
what should I do?
어떻게 해야 합니까?
Can I watch this?
이걸 봐도 될까요?
Haijun
하이준
I will take all the blame
모든 책임은 내가 짊어지겠다
Even if I go to hell, I will bear all the sins
지옥에 가더라도 모든 죄는 내가 짊어지리라
It's like you don't know anything
아무것도 모르는 것 같으니
Can't you just live like everyone else ?
그냥 남들처럼 살 수는 없나요 ?
Don't let him do something good that disgusts you next time
다음번에는 그 사람이 당신을 역겹게 만드는 좋은 일을 하게 두지 마세요
Because I will stop everything
다 멈출테니까
That's what I did
그게 내가 한 일이야
you cover it all
네가 다 덮어줘
This is how everything happened
모든 일이 이렇게 된 거야
if you do
당신이 그렇게한다면
If you throw away this cover
이 커버를 버리면
Do you think I can live well in your mind?
네 생각엔 내가 잘 살아갈 수 있을 것 같아?
Don't make excuses for my future
내 미래에 대해 변명하지 마세요
Covering everything , unable to relax
모든 것을 덮고 긴장을 풀 수 없다
It's because of your life that you turned a blind eye to that son's son
당신이 그 아들의 아들을 눈감은 것은 당신의 삶 때문입니다
lifetime
평생
I've been looking at your cold back all my life
난 평생 동안 너의 감기를 지켜봐왔어
no no
아니 아니
Even if I know this future
이 미래를 안다고 해도
Would you still choose this way?
그래도 이 방법을 선택하시겠습니까?
I even saw a bus in front of the grocery store
식료품점 앞에서 버스도 봤어
guess where
어딘지 맞춰봐
Well, it doesn't matter, I won't look for it anymore
뭐, 상관없어요. 더 이상 찾지 않겠습니다.
Why?
왜?
Teacher Yin Haijun just arrived
인하이준 선생님이 방금 오셨어요
what are you saying? Why is he in hospital now ?
당신이 무슨 말을하는거야? 그 사람은 지금 왜 병원에 있나요 ?
Defendant Yun Wulei's handwriting
피고인 윤우레이의 친필
He came and gave evidence
그 분이 오셔서 증거를 주셨는데
Did you find the evidence?
증거는 찾았나요?
Well I think I can finish it
글쎄, 마무리할 수 있을 것 같아
Thanks to him, I think we will be able to catch the real culprit this time
그 사람 덕분에 이번엔 진짜 범인을 잡을 수 있을 것 같아요
Didn't you ask where you came back from?
어디서 돌아왔는지 묻지 않았나요?
I heard it all
다 들었어
Can I not be discharged from the hospital now that I am fine ?
이제 괜찮으니 퇴원할 수는 없나요 ?
Certainly not yet
물론 아직은 아니다
I want to go home now
나는 지금 집에 가고 싶다
Grandpa says thank you
할아버지는 고맙다고 하신다
right in front of the grocery store
식료품점 바로 앞
I met the owner of Bom Bom teahouse
봄봄찻집 주인을 만났습니다
Which bus to take?
어느 버스를 탈까?
I didn't even think about parking
주차는 생각도 못했는데
I just keep looking at something
계속 뭔가만 쳐다보고 있어
Are you going on a long trip?
장거리 여행을 가시나요?
Yes
예
It will take time for the first car to arrive
첫 차가 도착하는 데 시간이 걸립니다
great whale whale
거대고래
I'll open the door in a moment, so stay inside
잠시 후 문을 열어드릴 테니 안에 계세요
It doesn't matter
그것은 중요하지 않습니다
Sister, I can do that too
언니, 나도 할 수 있어요
After losing my daughter
딸을 잃은 후
Worry about the world
세상에 대한 걱정
But the culprit was still caught, right?
그런데 범인은 아직 잡혔죠?
Yes
예
She is very pretty
그녀가 너무 예뻐요
Holding baby socks for a long time
아기 양말을 오랫동안 들고 있는 경우
I finally went up
드디어 올라갔어요
your mother
당신의 어머니
did you know?
알고 있었어?
Should I check where it went?
어디로 갔는지 확인해 봐야 할까요?
no i can
아니 할 수 있어
I heard that the suspect in the Wu Zongri serial murder case has been arrested
우종리 연쇄살인사건 용의자가 검거됐다는 소식을 들었습니다.
Briefly introduce the current status of the case
사건의 현재 상황을 간략하게 소개해주세요
Yes
예
Our police have spent the past five months
우리 경찰은 지난 5개월 동안
Three murders in Wuzhengli Village
우정리 마을에서 세 건의 살인 사건
two assassination plots
두 번의 암살 음모
The suspect was successfully captured
용의자 검거에 성공
The suspect Yun’s family studied abroad for a long time
피의자 윤씨 가족은 장기간 해외유학을 한 것으로 알려졌다.
A 20-year-old student
20세 학생
Because the criminal warrant has also expired.
형사 영장도 만료됐기 때문이다.
Yun family arrested
윤씨 일가 체포
After a thorough investigation into the intent and actions of the murder
살인의 의도와 행위를 철저히 조사한 후
will be handed over to investigators
수사팀에 넘겨질 예정
my God
맙소사
The director's son was born from a silkworm
감독의 아들은 누에에서 태어났다
You say that guy is the real culprit?
그 사람이 진짜 범인이라고요?
Wisdom and Peace and Prosperity
지혜와 평화와 번영
Not enough people have everything
모든 것을 갖춘 사람이 충분하지 않습니다.
Why do such a despicable act?
왜 그런 비열한 행동을 하는 걸까요?
- Ms.
- 씨
Can a poor man do it?
가난한 사람이 할 수 있나요?
- It's not that.
- 그게 아니야
My daughter was born like a bug
내 딸은 벌레 처럼 태어났어
those words
그 말
- Madam, this person is - Madam
- 부인, 이 사람은 - 부인
Miss
놓치다
The suspect in the Oh Jong-il serial murder case that happened one month ago
한 달 전 발생한 오정일 연쇄살인 사건의 용의자
He has been arrested and detained
그는 체포되어 구금되었습니다
For worried villagers, it's a nightmare
걱정하는 마을 사람들에게는 악몽이다
- It's over - Really
- 끝났어요 - 정말이에요
Reporter Kim Sun-woo
김선우 기자
The Wujingri serial murder case that occurred last month
지난달 발생한 우징리 연쇄살인사건
The suspect Yin Yin was arrested and taken to the police station
용의자 이인영을 체포해 경찰서로 연행했다.
Yunshi in camera lighting
카메라 조명 속의 윤시
He was taken to the interrogation room
그는 취조실로 끌려갔다
Although suspect Yoon Soo denied involvement in the murder
용의자 윤수는 살인 혐의를 부인했지만
Police found writing at the murder scene
경찰 , 살인 현장에서 유서 발견
It can be considered that the handwriting of the Yun family matches
윤씨 가문의 필체가 일치한다고 볼 수 있다.
It has been announced that the evidence has been obtained
증거자료를 확보했다고 발표되었습니다
I think it's all done now
이제 다 끝난 것 같아요
I think I've done all I can here since the culprit was also caught
범인도 잡혔으니까 여기서 할 수 있는 건 다 한 것 같아요.
The car has been repaired
자동차가 수리되었습니다
now we have to go back
이제 우리는 돌아가야 해
Shall we go out?
우리 나가볼까?
You can't live forever as a non-existent person
존재하지 않는 사람으로 영원히 살 수는 없다
The future of change must also be tested
변화의 미래도 테스트 해야합니다
Father, mother and family members
아버지, 어머니 그리고 가족들
Because I still need time to say goodbye
아직 이별할 시간이 필요하니까
How about going out tomorrow night?
내일 밤에 나가는 게 어때?
Excellent
훌륭한
I did this
나는 이걸했다
Do you want it?
당신은 그것을 원하십니까?
I do not want to go
나는 가고 싶지 않아
Have you not contacted my father yet ?
아직 아버지한테 연락 안 했어 ?
Believe me, I'll avoid it for a while, so I'll talk it out
믿어줘 당분간은 피해갈 테니까 얘기해 볼게
Yes
예
I wonder who this lucky guy will be
이 행운의 남자는 누구일지 궁금하네요
Finally, it happens to you
마침내 그런 일이 당신에게 일어납니다
There is always money in front of the store and plenty of toothpaste
가게 앞에는 항상 돈이 있고 치약도 넉넉하다
very good
매우 좋은
What gift did you receive from your boyfriend?
남자친구한테 어떤 선물을 받았나요?
- do you have a boyfriend?
- 남자친구 있어요?
ha
하아
- Not yet - Ha
- 아직은 - 하하
- If you don't buy again - it's too late
- 다시 구매하지 않으면 너무 늦습니다
Are you crazy?
제정신이에요?
Is 200,000 a bit too much?
200,000은 좀 너무한거 아닌가요?
Why are you doing this to me?
나한테 왜 이러는 걸까요?
you don't have enough money
당신은 돈이 충분하지 않습니다
Did you steal the teacher's money?
선생님 돈을 훔쳤나요?
- If it slips, it's me.. - Hey
- 미끄러지면 나야.. - 야
Because I was told that if I was late I would have to pay back the money
늦으면 돈을 갚아야 한다고 해서
Without saying a word, he picked up the guitar and left.
그는 아무 말도 없이 기타를 들고 떠났다.
My ears hurt like hell
귀가 존나 아프다
ha
하아
It's really you now
이제 정말 너야
- Thank you, guest - Madam
- 감사합니다, 손님 - 부인
(Sun and Moon Record Store)
(해와 달 레코드 가게)
Miss
놓치다
Unless you're not
당신이 그렇지 않다면
With the feeling I like...
내가 좋아하는 느낌으로..
Just a bribe
그냥 뇌물이지
forward
앞으로
I wish my best friend Sun Ai all the best for the rest of his life
내 가장 친한 친구인 Sun Ai가 남은 생애 동안 최선을 다하길 바랍니다
If you make Shan'e cry once
Shan'e를 한 번 울게 하면
I won't put it here
여기에는 넣지 않겠습니다
Bribe or threat?
뇌물인가, 협박인가?
I'll look into it myself
내가 직접 조사해 볼게
Why are you..
너는 왜..
What a nuisance
정말 귀찮은 일이군요
I said they will always be by each other's side, never separated
늘 서로 곁에 있을 거라고 말했지, 결코 헤어지지 않을 거라
this is me
이게 나야
Because we can see you again
다시 볼 수 있으니까
where are you going?
어디 가세요?
see you soon
곧 봐요
It may take you longer
시간이 더 오래 걸릴 수도 있습니다
what are you saying?
당신이 무슨 말을하는거야?
But you 're not the one with the headache anymore?
그런데 더 이상 두통을 앓고 있는 사람은 당신이 아니신가요?
He doesn't seem to have a fever
열은 없는 것 같다
ok let's go
확인 가자
I don't feel well
기분이 좋지 않아요
Dad, I must do it this time
아빠 이번엔 꼭 해봐야겠어요
without illness
질병 없이
no harm
해를 끼치 지 않습니다
Customize everything you want
원하는 모든 것을 맞춤 설정하세요
Why do you really want to kill me?
왜 정말로 나를 죽이고 싶나요?
This is what I want to continue to ask
계속 묻고 싶은 건 이것이다.
now we will never know
이제 우리는 결코 알지 못할 것이다
Because the future that could kill me has disappeared
날 죽일 수도 있는 미래가 사라졌으니 까
(Safety first, always safe)
(안전 제일, 언제나 안전)
interesting
흥미로운
( Chuo Ah, owner of Bom Bom Teahouse )
( 봄봄 찻집 주인 아츄오)
("Wu Zongri's family is ruined")
("우종리 가문은 망했다")
("A Girl Was Killed")
("소녀가 살해당했습니다")
(" After two 20-year-old girls were killed in succession")
(" 20대 소녀 2명이 연달아 살해된 후")
("The whole village was panicked")
("마을 전체가 패닉에 빠졌습니다")
(Test results)
(시험 결과)
(Time travel system, user manual)
(시간여행 시스템, 사용설명서)
Oh, is there such a thing?
아, 그런 것도 있나요?
You also died because of me
너도 나 때문에 죽었어
Did he come back for revenge?
복수를 위해 돌아온 걸까요?
If you want to know this much
이만큼 알고 싶다면
Just stay like this
그냥 이대로 있어줘
This time it’s to avoid getting caught
이번에는 들키지 않으려고
Then do it again
그럼 다시 해봐
let's kill it
죽여버리자
No matter how far you live
아무리 멀리 살아도
I didn't realize there were other forms
다른 형태가 있다는 걸 몰랐어요
What
무엇
clear proof
명확한 증거
After finding the letter from my girlfriend
여자친구가 보낸 편지를 찾은 후
I would like to know
나는 알고 싶다
Haijun
하이준
(I hope you will definitely use the diary I gave you as a gift)
(제가 선물해드린 다이어리 꼭 활용하시길 바랍니다)
you are a smart person
당신은 똑똑한 사람입니다
You didn't leave any footprints at the scene
현장에 발자국도 남기지 않으셨군요
Why did you miss it?
왜 놓쳤나요?
Just knowing that you will definitely become a witness is enough
반드시 증인이 될 거라는 걸 아는 것만으로도 충분해
That woman and that...
그 여자랑 그 사람...
I knew I could end it all
난 내가 모든 걸 끝낼 수 있다는 걸 알았어
Why did you leave it to that woman?
왜 그 여자한테 맡겼어요?
Have you ever loved?
사랑해본 적 있나요?
I asked a very unexpected question
정말 예상치 못한 질문을 했어요
Why and how did he kill?
그는 왜, 어떻게 죽였는가?
I thought I would ask
물어볼 줄 알았는데
Is this love?
이게 사랑인가요?
i love it
나는 그것을 좋아한다
I thought he was the one who could make my dream come true
내 꿈을 이뤄줄 수 있는 사람이 바로 그 사람이라고 생각했어요
Because he thought things would be different
그는 상황이 달라질 것이라고 생각했기 때문에
I used to know
나는 알고 있었다
Than a cruel woman
잔인한 여자보다
I remember that woman's face
나는 그 여자의 얼굴을 기억한다
I usually read books
나는 보통 책을 읽는다.
once Upon a time
옛날 옛적에
He never looked at me with warm eyes
그 사람은 한 번도 나를 따뜻한 눈으로 바라보지 않았어
Finally when I was 7 years old
마침내 내가 7살이 되었을 때
("Nesach")
("네사크")
i left home
나는 집을 떠났다
Then I said I don't want to be my mother anymore
그러다가 더 이상 엄마가 되고 싶지 않다고 말했어요
I..
나..
Am I going to see my mother?
내가 엄마를 만나러 갈까?
Mother
어머니
Did you hear from mom?
엄마한테 들었어?
more than anyone else
누구보다
From someone who will absolutely love you
당신을 절대적으로 사랑할 사람에게서
Abandoned
버려진
You know that feeling?
그 느낌 아시죠?
I miss the person who abandoned me every day
날 버린 그 사람이 매일 그리워요
cried all night
밤새 울었다
in endless pain
끝없는 고통 속에서
I agreed
나는 동의했다
next time
다음번
if i had a child
나에게 아이가 있었다면
to my son
내 아들에게
My son will never be like me
내 아들은 절대 나처럼 되지 않을 거야
I met a woman who loves her children more than anyone else
누구보다 자식을 사랑하는 여자를 만났어요
As long as you are happy
당신이 행복하다면
That's why I found it
그래서 찾았어요
Such a woman
그런 여자
That woman...
그 여자...
orphan
유아
A woman who really wants a family
가족을 진심으로 원하는 여자
Did you know this was going to happen?
이런 일이 일어날 줄 알았나요?
- What - you want to create so much
- 뭐 - 만들고 싶은 게 너무 많아
perfect happiness, perfect family
완벽한 행복, 완벽한 가족
Do you know it was destroyed by your own hands?
당신의 손으로 파괴된 것을 알고 계십니까?
What's that word?
그 단어는 무엇입니까?
That's why it's still good
그렇기 때문에 아직도 좋다.
from people like you
당신 같은 사람들로부터
my mother escaped
엄마가 탈출했어
you..
너..
Unless you're not...
당신이 아닌 이상...
impossible
불가능한
if you really are my son
네가 정말 내 아들이라면
you can't do this to me
넌 나 한테 이러면 안 돼
How could I kill you?
내가 어떻게 당신을 죽일 수 있습니까?
With a despicable father like you
너같은 비열한 아버지와 함께
Abandoned from birth, I tell you
태어날 때부터 버림받았다고 말해요
what you have said so far
당신이 지금까지 말한 것
The victim’s feelings and the murderer’s speechless
피해자의 감정과 살인자의 말문이 막힌다
Just false words
거짓된 말뿐
So go ahead and spend all your time doing this for the rest of your life
그러니 남은 생애 동안 이 일을 하면서 모든 시간을 보내십시오.
Get trapped, feel the pain, and survive
갇혀서 고통을 느끼며 살아남으세요
This is what makes you want to have kids so bad
이것이 당신이 아이를 그토록 갖고 싶어하게 만드는 이유입니다
These are the last words you say as a son
이것은 당신이 아들로서 하는 마지막 말입니다
- Mr. Yin -Ms.
- 음 씨 - Ms.
- Yes ma'am
- 네 부인
Why are they going out? Is there a problem?
그들은 왜 나가는 걸까요? 문제가 있습니까?
So, is it possible to live without problems?
그렇다면 문제 없이 살 수 있을까?
I'm moving tonight
나 오늘 밤에 이사할 거야
Why did it suddenly happen without any warning?
왜 아무런 예고도 없이 갑자기 그런 일이 일어났는가?
I am really sorry
정말 미안해요
- Yes - I'm very sorry, sir.
- 네 - 정말 죄송합니다.
How to do what I consider a family thing ..
내가 가족의 일이라고 생각하는 일을 하는 방법 ..
we will really meet again
우리 진짜 다시 만날 거야
when
언제
Where
어디
34 years old
34세
at your home
너의 집에서
i really hate you
난 정말 당신이 싫어요
Instead, try saying you won't see each other for the rest of your lives
대신 평생 안 보자고 해보세요.
Try to say you won't see me again
다시는 날 볼 수 없을 거라고 말해봐
let us wait no longer
더 이상 기다리지 말자
around that time
그 무렵
Although it's a little different now
지금은 좀 달라졌지만
I really like this face too
나도 이 얼굴 정말 좋아해
That face too
그 얼굴도
i miss it very much
정말 그리워요
I think it's great to be here
여기 있어서 정말 좋은 것 같아요
current
현재의
Because I can see you now
이제 널 볼 수 있으니까
i can take it back
다시 가져갈 수 있어
I think it's really good
정말 좋은 것 같아요
Me too
저도요
I'm very pleased to meet you..
만나서 정말 반가워요..
I was very happy then
그때는 정말 행복했어요
Thanks
감사해요
Thank you Mr. Yin
감사합니다 이인씨
Because he is my neighbor
그 사람은 내 이웃이니까
- Thank you very much - Yes
- 정말 고마워요 - 네
thanks for saying that
그렇게 말해줘서 고마워
Miss
놓치다
Thank you very much sisters for helping me
도와주신 언니들 정말 감사해요
That's cool
멋지네요
Can't you tell me where you're going?
어디로 가는지 말해 줄 수 없나요?
Now let us know it must be somewhere
이제 어딘가에 있을 거라고 알려주세요
no matter where
어디든 상관없어
a bit too far
조금 너무 멀다
Stay healthy and live longer
건강하게 오래오래 살아요
I will continue to see you
나는 당신을 계속 볼 것입니다
we really left
우리 정말 떠났어
Yes, sir
알겠습니다
Time travel long after
오랜만에 시간여행
a little excited
조금 흥분
Are you not immune?
면역이 없나요?
What?
무엇?
He came back without saying goodbye
그 사람은 작별 인사도 없이 돌아왔어
grandfather and mother
할아버지와 어머니
Especially with my mom, I don't know if this is the last time I'll be here
특히 엄마와 함께라면 이번이 마지막이 될지 모르겠습니다.
I'm not here to see them
나는 그들을 보러 여기 온 것이 아니다
That's it, I've seen it a lot
그렇구나, 많이 봤지
enough
충분한
What will you do first when you come back?
돌아오면 가장 먼저 무엇을 할 거예요?
what do you want to do?
뭐하고 싶어?
Iced Caramel Macchiato
아이스 카라멜 마키아토
Let's have a drink of something very sweet
아주 달콤한 거 한잔 하자
Do you know how delicious it tastes with salty bread?
짭짤한 빵과 함께 먹으면 얼마나 맛있는지 아시나요?
Really like sweet and salty
정말 달콤하고 짠맛이 좋아
so exciting
너무 신난다
Don't worry
괜찮아요
It's over in the blink of an eye
눈 깜짝할 사이에 끝났어
Once you pass this cave
이 동굴을 지나면
Just like lying on our home field
마치 홈그라운드에 누워있는 것처럼
Will return in 2021
2021년에 돌아올 것이다
OK, let's go
확인 가자
Are you there yet?
아직 거기 있나요?
Is it 2021?
2021년인가요?
Smoother than expected
예상보다 매끄럽다
I'm not sure if I'll be back after a long time
오랜만에 다시 돌아올지 모르겠네요
Yes, this year is 2021
네, 올해는 2021년이에요
Yes or no?
예 혹은 아니오?
- Mr. Yin- Yes, yes
- 인 씨 - 네, 네
Hey Mr. Yin
안녕하세요 인씨님
Didn’t I say I would be a news anchor in 2021?
제가 2021년에 뉴스앵커가 된다고 하지 않았나요?
June 14, 1987
1987년 6월 14일
10:40pm
오후 10시 40분
We 've made everything perfect here
우리 는 여기서 모든 것을 완벽하게 만들었습니다.
I tried to leave, but I stayed here like before
떠나려 했지만 예전처럼 여기에 머물렀어
Say we are forever...
우리는 영원하다고 말해줘...
Is fate trapped here?
여기에 운명이 갇힌 걸까요?
(The finale will be broadcast at 9:50 pm tomorrow)
(내일 밤 9시 50분 최종회 방송)
(a stranger I met)
(내가 만난 낯선 사람)